<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Moltony&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Moltony&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 22:16:39 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>libNDS&#39;s PCX loader is weird</title>
      <link>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/libnds-pcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 22:16:39 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/libnds-pcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last time I talked about how GIMP makes incorrect PCX files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess what? Turns out I was &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WRONG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, all the PCX files that come with libNDS are 8bpp - they can have up to 256 unique colors. But when you tell GIMP to create an indexed image with maximum color count of 256 and you have less than or equal to 16 colors in the image, it will get crushed to 2bpp or 4bpp. libNDS doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize 2 and 4bpp images for some reason, so it just gives up&amp;hellip;and I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, libNDS docs &lt;strong&gt;did not&lt;/strong&gt; specify that only 8bpp images are supported, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very unexpected that I assumed that GIMP is the problem. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get around this arbitrary limitation, I use IfranView to increase the color depth to 8bpp. It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to do - one just needs to open their image, click on &amp;lsquo;Image&amp;rsquo; and then on &amp;lsquo;Increase Color Depth&amp;rsquo;, select 8bpp and save the new image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you have to update many images to 8bpp, then it can take a really long time. A reeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeally long time. A r{&amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo; * math.inf}ally long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- moltony&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GIMP and PCX: a disappointing discovery</title>
      <link>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/gimp-and-pcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 14:10:10 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/gimp-and-pcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get PCX image files to load using libnds. I knew that GIMP supports many image formats, including PCX, so I made a new PCX image, saved it and then wrote code that displays it. After some tweaking&amp;hellip; I got a cyan square. Weird! I started messing around with the code, trying to get it to work, but it either didn&amp;rsquo;t display anything or displayed that dreaded cyan square. Looking at the documentation, I decided to print the BPP of the image, and&amp;hellip; 1bpp. The image that I made was 8bpp, but the PCX loader thought it&amp;rsquo;s 1bpp. So there must have been some issue with GIMP not saving my image properly. I tested the program with &lt;code&gt;ball.pcx&lt;/code&gt;, which is included in libnds examples and is known to work. And sure enough, it just worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never using GIMP for PCX files ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- moltony&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 03:20:08 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iammoltony.github.io/blog/public/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first ever blog page. I am so excited!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this blog, I will post things I find quite interesting, so stay tuned! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- moltony&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
